Now that we learned about the likelihood function,
والآن بعد أن تعلمنا حول دالة الاحتمال،
the thing that were trying to maximize, let's talk about gradient ascent algorithm
وهو الشيء الذي نحاول تكبيره، دعونا نتحدث عن خوارزمية التدرج التصاعدي
that tries to make it as large as possible.
التي تحاول جعلها كبيرة بقدر الإمكان.
In this section, were going to go through a little bit of math, a little bit of
في هذا القسم، سنخوض في القليل من الرياضيات، مع القليل من
detail but in the end, the gradient ascent algorithm for learning a logistic
التفصيل لكن في النهاية، فإن خوارزمية تعلم التدرج التصاعدي
regression classifier is going to be extremely simple and extremely intuitive.
لتصنيف الانحدار اللوجستي ستكون بسيطة للغاية وبديهية للغاية.
Even if the likelihood function's a little bit fuzzy for you and the gradient
لذا حتى وإن كان دالة الاحتمال غامضة بعض الشيء بالنسبة لك وكانت أمور التدرج
stuff's not totally clear but in the end, the algorithm that you're going to
غير واضحة تمامًا ولكن في نهاية المطاف، فإن الخوارزمية التي ستقوم
implement is going to be something that only requires a few lines of code.
بتنفيذها سوف تكون واحدة تتطلب فقط بضعة أسطر من التعليمات البرمجية.
In fact, you'll be able to do that extremely easy.
وفي الواقع، ستكون قادرًا على القيام بذلك بشكلٍ سهل للغاية.
Good.
جيد.
We defined the model we want to fit, the logistic regression model,
لقد حددنا النموذج الذي نريد مطابقته، نموذج الانحدار اللوجستي
we talked about the quality max trick, the likelihood function,
وتحدثنا عن خدعة زيادة الجودة، دالة الاحتمال،
now we're going to define the gradient ascent algorithm.
والآن سنقوم بتعريف خوارزمية التدرج التصاعدي.
Which is machine learning algorithm that tries to make the likelihood function as large
وهو خوارزمية تعلم آلي تحاول أن تجعل دالة الاحتمال كبيرة قدر الإمكان
as possible to find their famous W hat fits our data really well.
للعثور على معامل W hat الشهير الخاص بها الذي يناسب البيانات بشكلٍ جيد حقًا.
Now, we can go back to this picture that we've seen a few times where
والآن، يمكننا أن نعود إلى هذه الصورة التي رأيناها عدة مرات حيث يكون
we have multiple lines and they have likelihood function and
لدينا خطوط متعددة ولديها دالة احتمال
we're trying to find the one that has best likelihood.
ونحن نسعى لإيجاد واحدة تحتوي على أفضل احتمالات
This line here with the W0 = 1, W1 = 0.5, W2 = -1.5.
هذا الخط هنا مع W0 = 1 و W1 = 0.5 وW2 = -1.5.
We now know that the likelihood function is exactly this function up here.
ونحن نعلم الآن أن دالة الاحتمال هي هذه الدالة هنا تمامًا.
The product over my data point of the probability of the true label
والناتج عبر نقاط البيانات لاحتمالية التسمية الحقيقية
given the input centers that we have.
مع إعطاء مراكز الإدخال التي لدينا.
Our goal is to take this l and
لذا فإن هدفنا أن تأخذ L هذه وتحسينها
optimize it with gradient ascent.
باستخدام التدرج التصاعدي.
That's what we're going to go after right now.
وهذا ما سنقوم بفعله الآن.
As a quick, quick, quick review, we have our likelihood function and
كمراجعة سريعة للغاية، لدينا دالة احتمال
when I find the parameter values that take this likelihood function,
عندما أجد قيم المتغير التي تأخذ دالة الاحتمال هذه،
so that this is the W0, W1, W2,
بحيث تكون هذه هي W0، W1، W2،
which is a function of three parameters in this little example over here.
وهي دالة لثلاثة متغيرات في هذا المثال الصغير هنا.
We're trying to find the maximum over all possible parameters W0,
ونحن نحاول إيجاد الحد الأقصى عبر كافة المتغيرات المحتملة W0،
W1, and W2 and there's infinitely many of those, so
W1، وW2 وهناك العديد من تلك المتغيرات بلا حدود، وبالتالي
if you try to enumerate it will be impossible to try them all.
إذا حاولت تعدادها فسيكون من المستحيل تجربتها جميعًا.
But gradient ascent is this magically simple but wonderful algorithm where you
ولكن التدرج التصاعدي هو هذه الخوارزمية السحرية البسيطة لكن رائعة حيث يمكنك
start from some point over here in the parameter space,
البدء من نقطة معينة هنا في مساحة المتغير
which might be the weight for awful is 0, the weight for awesome is -6.
والذي قد يكون الترجيح لـ awful هو 0، والترجيح لـ awesome هو -6.
And you slowly climb up the hill in order to find the optimum,
ويمكنك ببطء تسلق التل بغية إيجاد النقطة القصوى،
the top of the hill here, which going to be our famous W hat.
وهي الجزء العلوي من التل هنا، التي ستكون W hat الشهيرة.
They might say that the weight for awesome is,
قد تقول إن ترجيح awesome هو،
it's probably going to be a positive number, so maybe somewhere like this,
ربما سيكون رقمًا موجبًا، لذا ربما في مكان ما مثل هذا،
say 0.5 and the weight for awful is maybe -1.
فلنقل 0.5 وترجيح awful هو ربما -1.
Now in this plot, I've only shown two of the coordinates W1 and W2.
الآن في هذا الرسم، أظهرت فقط اثنين من إحداثيات W1 وW2.
I didn't show W0 because it's really hard to plot in four-dimensional space.
زلم أظهر W0 لأنه من الصعب حقًا الرسم في مساحة رباعية الأبعاد.
Four dimensions, so I'm just showing you three out of those four dimensions.
أربعة أبعاد، لذا أنا فقط أريك ثلاثة من هذه الأبعاد الأربعة.
Now, let's discuss the gradient ascent algorithm to go ahead and do that.
والآن، دعونا نناقش خوارزمية التدرج التصاعدي للمضي قدمًا والقيام بذلك.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]